Methods of Counting Defect Opportunities
Hello, Mike Harry back with you again. Where we’re pursuing the topic of defect opportunities.
Recall the example where we worked through solder joints.
Let's look at some other examples, of defect categories in some different areas.
In this particular case, we see from the EPA, a defective vehicle notice.
And down here is a defect report of what could go wrong.
So, it says right here that an authorized officer
suspects or is satisfied that your vehicle
did not comply with the state legislation on environment.
So, you got to do the following repairs. In other words, these are the defect categories.
Those are the opportunities for something to be wrong with your car.
Here's a similar type thing, a report form
from a particular local government, looking at the
information coming in from citizens concerning the road condition.
I wish to report the following matter.
I saw an abandoned vehicle. There is debris on the road and so on.
There's lots of chances.
See, here's a type of a defect in software, error connecting to service manager.
And here's another one, what kind of message would you like to send?
This is software related. Oh, I had a bug, or had a problem.
Or praise. We see a bug or a problem, a bug is definitely a defect.
See, there's another one reporting a problem.
Here is a receipt discrepancy report,
complete with a disposition, asking you to explain the discrepancy.
Well, there are different types of discrepancies.
Many, many different ways to look at defects.
Here's one a reconciliation report.
The reconciled amount was, had a differential $122.68.
That's a defect. That's a type of defect. That's a defect opportunity.
Here's a punch list report from construction.
Punch list is something that's wrong, that has to be repaired, following construction.
Somebody goes around, either the owner and inspector, looks at the site,
and sees different things wrong and they fill out a punch list.
Check off the box, these are the things that are wrong.
Here's one that works very specifically,
looking for all kinds of information.
Even involving defect complexity.
A quality database here defects.
Now, sometimes our defects are distributed within an area.
Not within discrete things, but across an area.
And the area of opportunity would come into play there now.
The number of defects per square inch of material,
or per square yard, or per cubic meter.
Where the base of the opportunity is area,
not discrete accounts of things.
So, there's lots of ways to look at those.
And creates a discussion of our opportunities
for defect, or defect opportunities as we call them.
And again we're reminded, what must be right?
Well, whatever shouldn't be wrong.
And what could go wrong? Well, things that must've went right.
So again, you see we’re working on the same coin,
different sides, when we ask the two different questions.
But where Six Sigma is concerned, we focus on defect opportunities.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.